<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DementiaApp</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Notifications</string>

    <!--register.xml-->
    <string name="username">Username</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="register_button">Register</string>

    <string name="channel_name">Notification</string>
    <string name="channel_description">Daily Notification</string>

    <string name="sp1">1. Memory loss</string>
    <string name="sp2">2. Difficulty with communication</string>
    <string name="sp3">3. Poor judgment</string>
    <string name="sp4">4. Confusion and disorientation</string>
    <string name="sp5">5. Changes in mood and behavior</string>
    <string name="sp6">6. Problems with daily activities</string>
    <string name="sp7">7. Loss of initiative</string>
    <string name="sd1">In the early stages of dementia, people may have trouble remembering recent events or conversations. As the disease progresses, they may have difficulty remembering names of family members and friends, where they live or how to get there, or how to complete familiar tasks like cooking a meal. They may also repeat questions or stories, sometimes within a short period.</string>
    <string name="sd2">Communication difficulties in people with dementia can manifest in many ways. They may have trouble finding the right words or using language effectively, struggle to follow a conversation, or have trouble understanding what others are saying. They may also have difficulty expressing themselves, leading to frustration or anger.</string>
    <string name="sd3">People with dementia may make poor decisions that put them at risk. They may forget to take medication, give money to strangers, or engage in other behaviors that could lead to harm. They may also have difficulty understanding the consequences of their actions, making it difficult for them to recognize that they need help.</string>
    <string name="sd4">Confusion and disorientation are common symptoms of dementia. People may become easily confused or disoriented in unfamiliar places or situations. They may forget the time or date, become lost, or have difficulty recognizing people they know.</string>
    <string name="sd5">Mood and behavior changes can be difficult to manage for both people with dementia and their caregivers. People with dementia may become more agitated, anxious, or depressed, or experience mood swings. They may also become more socially isolated, lose interest in activities they used to enjoy, or exhibit changes in personality.</string>
    <string name="sd6">As dementia progresses, people may have difficulty with routine tasks such as dressing, grooming, or preparing meals. They may forget how to do these activities or find them too complex to complete independently. This can lead to frustration or embarrassment.</string>
    <string name="sd7">People with dementia may lose interest in activities they used to enjoy or become less motivated to engage with the world around them. They may require prompting to complete daily tasks or engage in social activities.</string>

    <string name="tp1">1. Speak clearly and calmly</string>
    <string name="tp2">2. Use nonverbal cues</string>
    <string name="tp3">3. Be patient</string>
    <string name="tp4">4. Listen attentively</string>
    <string name="tp5">5. Avoid correcting or arguing</string>
    <string name="tp6">6. Use positive body language</string>
    <string name="tp7">7. Break down tasks into smaller steps</string>
    <string name="tp8">8. Create a calm environment</string>
    <string name="td1">Speak clearly and calmly: People with dementia may have difficulty understanding complex language or sentences, so it is important to speak in simple, clear language. Speak in a calm and reassuring tone of voice, as this can help put the person at ease and make them more receptive to what you are saying.</string>
    <string name="td2">Use nonverbal cues: Nonverbal cues such as facial expressions, gestures, and touch can help reinforce your message and provide additional information to the person. For example, if you are trying to communicate that you care about them, you might offer a gentle touch on the hand or a smile.</string>
    <string name="td3">People with dementia may take longer to process information and respond to questions, so it is important to be patient and give them plenty of time to respond. Avoid rushing them or interrupting them, as this can increase their frustration and anxiety.</string>
    <string name="td4">Listening attentively to what the person is saying can help you understand their needs and concerns. Try to focus on the person and avoid distractions such as your phone or other conversations. Pay attention to their tone of voice, body language, and facial expressions, as these can provide important cues about their emotions and needs.</string>
    <string name="td5">People with dementia may become confused or forgetful, so it is important to avoid correcting or arguing with them. Instead, try to redirect the conversation or change the subject to something more positive and familiar. For example, if they are talking about a deceased loved one, you might redirect the conversation to a happy memory you shared with that person.</string>
    <string name="td6">Positive body language such as smiling, nodding, and maintaining eye contact can help reinforce your message and make the person feel more comfortable and at ease. This can also help build trust and rapport with the person.</string>
    <string name="td7">People with dementia may have difficulty completing complex tasks, so it can be helpful to break them down into smaller, more manageable steps. This can help them feel more in control and reduce their anxiety and frustration.</string>
    <string name="td8">Creating a calm and quiet environment free from distractions can help the person focus on the conversation and make it easier for them to understand what you are saying. Turn off the TV or radio, close the door, and minimize other distractions as much as possible.</string>

    <string name="dp1">1. Identify triggers</string>
    <string name="dp2">2. Remain calm</string>
    <string name="dp3">3.  attention</string>
    <string name="dp4">4. Provide reassurance</string>
    <string name="dp5">5. Use validation therapy</string>
    <string name="dp6">6. Maintain a routine</string>
    <string name="dp7">7. Seek professional help</string>
    <string name="dd1">Triggers are events or situations that may cause a person with dementia to exhibit troubling behavior. Common triggers include loud noises, unfamiliar environments, and changes in routine. By identifying triggers, you can anticipate and prevent the behavior from occurring. For example, if you notice that the person becomes agitated when there is too much noise, you might try reducing the noise level in the environment by turning off the TV or closing windows.</string>
    <string name="dd2">When a person with dementia exhibits troubling behavior, it is important to remain calm and composed. This can help prevent the behavior from escalating and make the person feel more comfortable and secure. Try to speak in a calm and reassuring tone of voice, and avoid becoming confrontational or argumentative.</string>
    <string name="dd3">Redirecting the person is attention to a different activity or topic can help prevent troubling behavior from occurring. For example, if the person becomes agitated when they are unable to leave the house, you might suggest going for a walk or engaging in a different activity that they enjoy. This can help distract the person from the behavior and provide them with a sense of purpose and fulfillment.</string>
    <string name="dd4">People with dementia may become anxious or agitated when they are unsure of their surroundings or situation. Providing reassurance can help alleviate their anxiety and reduce troubling behaviors. For example, if the person is feeling anxious or scared, you might say "You are safe here with me, I will take care of you." This can help the person feel more secure and reduce the likelihood of troubling behavior.</string>
    <string name="dd5">Validation therapy involves acknowledging and validating the person\'s feelings and emotions, even if they do not make sense or are based on false beliefs. This can help reduce the person\'s anxiety and provide them with a sense of validation and acceptance. For example, if the person believes that they need to go to work, you might acknowledge their feelings and say "It sounds like you really miss your job. Let\'s talk about some of the things you enjoyed about your work." This can help redirect the person\'s attention and provide them with a sense of purpose and fulfillment.</string>
    <string name="dd6">People with dementia often feel more comfortable and less anxious when they have a consistent routine. Establishing a regular routine for the person can help reduce troubling behavior and provide them with a sense of structure and predictability. For example, you might establish a regular routine for meals, exercise, and social interaction. This can help the person feel more secure and reduce the likelihood of troubling behavior.</string>
    <string name="dd7">If the troubling behavior persists or becomes too challenging to manage on your own, consider seeking professional help from a doctor or mental health professional who specializes in dementia care. They can provide you with additional strategies and resources for managing troubling behavior and help ensure the safety and well-being of the person with dementia.</string>

    <!--Quiz - Symptom B,C,B,B,B,A,B,B,B,B-->
    <string name="q1">1. What is the most common early symptom of dementia?</string>
    <string name="a1">A. Difficulty speaking</string>
    <string name="b1">B. Memory loss</string>
    <string name="c1">C. Trouble with coordination</string>
    <string name="d1">D. Loss of sense of smell</string>

    <string name="q2">2. Which of the following is a common symptom of dementia?</string>
    <string name="a2">A. Increased sense of taste</string>
    <string name="b2">B. Improved problem-solving abilities</string>
    <string name="c2">C. Difficulty with decision-making</string>
    <string name="d2">D. Enhanced sense of hearing</string>

    <string name="q3">3. Changes in mood or personality are not common symptoms of dementia.</string>
    <string name="a3">A. True</string>
    <string name="b3">B. False</string>

    <string name="q4">4. Which of the following is not a common symptom of dementia?</string>
    <string name="a4">A. Difficulty finding words</string>
    <string name="b4">B. Trouble sleeping</string>
    <string name="c4">C. Misplacing things</string>
    <string name="d4">D. Poor judgment</string>

    <string name="q5">5. What is the term used to describe the inability to recognize familiar faces or objects?</string>
    <string name="a5">A. Apraxia</string>
    <string name="b5">B. Agnosia</string>
    <string name="c5">C. Aphasia</string>
    <string name="d5">D. Anomia</string>

    <string name="q6">6. Losing interest in hobbies and activities is a common symptom of dementia.</string>
    <string name="a6">A. True</string>
    <string name="b6">B. False</string>

    <string name="q7">7. What is the term used to describe a sudden and intense confusion in a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="a7">A. Sundowning</string>
    <string name="b7">B. Delirium</string>
    <string name="c7">C. Hypoxia</string>
    <string name="d7">D. Ataxia</string>

    <string name="q8">8. What is the term used to describe a sudden and intense confusion in a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="a8">A. Visual hallucinations</string>
    <string name="b8">B. Difficulty with language</string>
    <string name="c8">C. Tremors</string>
    <string name="d8">D. Apathy</string>

    <string name="q9">9. Difficulty with spatial orientation is not a common symptom of dementia.</string>
    <string name="a9">A. True</string>
    <string name="b9">B. False</string>

    <string name="q10">10. What is the term used to describe a sudden and intense confusion in a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="a10">A. Agitation</string>
    <string name="b10">B. Perseveration</string>
    <string name="c10">C. Apathy</string>
    <string name="d10">D. Hallucination</string>

    <!--Quiz - Tips C,A,C,D,B,C,C,B,C,D-->
    <string name="pq1">1. What is one tip for communicating with a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="pa1">A. Speak quickly and loudly</string>
    <string name="pb1">B. Use complex sentences and vocabulary</string>
    <string name="pc1">C. Use simple and direct language</string>
    <string name="pd1">D. Talk to them like they are a child</string>

    <string name="pq2">2. It is helpful to use nonverbal cues like facial expressions and gestures when.</string>
    <string name="pa2">A. True</string>
    <string name="pb2">B. False</string>

    <string name="pq3">3. What is one way to show that you are actively listening to a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="pa3">A. Interrupting them when they are speaking</string>
    <string name="pb3">B. Finishing their sentences for them</string>
    <string name="pc3">C. Nodding your head and maintaining eye contact</string>
    <string name="pd3">D. Checking your phone during the conversation</string>

    <string name="pq4">4. What is one way to avoid confusing a person with dementia during a conversation?</string>
    <string name="pa4">A. Using abstract language and concepts</string>
    <string name="pb4">B. Asking them to recall specific dates and events</string>
    <string name="pc4">C. Changing the topic frequently</string>
    <string name="pd4">D. Sticking to one topic at a time</string>

    <string name="pq5">5. It is helpful to use humor and sarcasm when communicating with someone with dementia.</string>
    <string name="pa5">A. True</string>
    <string name="pb5">B. False</string>

    <string name="pq6">6. What is one way to help a person with dementia understand what you are saying?</string>
    <string name="pa6">A. Speaking louder and more forcefully</string>
    <string name="pb6">B. Repeating the same thing over and over</string>
    <string name="pc6">C. Using visual aids like pictures or gestures</string>
    <string name="pd6">D. Talking faster</string>

    <string name="pq7">7. What is one way to encourage a person with dementia to communicate with you?</string>
    <string name="pa7">A. Asking them questions that require complex answers</string>
    <string name="pb7">B. Talking to them while they are distracted or busy</string>
    <string name="pc7">C. Being patient and giving them time to respond</string>
    <string name="pd7">D. Ignoring them if they seem confused or disoriented</string>

    <string name="pq8">8. It is helpful to argue with a person with dementia if they say something that is not true.</string>
    <string name="pa8">A. True</string>
    <string name="pb8">B. False</string>

    <string name="pq9">9. What is one way to help a person with dementia feel more comfortable during a conversation?</string>
    <string name="pa9">A. Speaking to them from a distance</string>
    <string name="pb9">B. Standing over them or towering over them</string>
    <string name="pc9">C. Sitting down at their level and maintaining eye contact</string>
    <string name="pd9">D. Using a lot of technical jargon and industry-specific language</string>

    <string name="pq10">10. What is one way to show empathy and compassion when communicating with a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="pa10">A. Ignoring their feelings and concerns</string>
    <string name="pb10">B. Rushing them through the conversation</string>
    <string name="pc10">C. Being dismissive of their needs and requests</string>
    <string name="pd10">D. Validating their feelings and offering support</string>

    <!--Quiz - Dealing  A,A,B,B,A,B.C.A,C,D-->
    <string name="gq1">1. What is one way to help prevent agitation and confusion in a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="ga1">A. Keep their routine the same every day</string>
    <string name="gb1">B. Change their routine frequently</string>
    <string name="gc1">C. Avoid providing cues to help them remember things</string>
    <string name="gd1">D. Speak to them in a loud and aggressive tone</string>

    <string name="gq2">2. It is important to be patient and understanding when interacting with a person with dementia, even if they exhibit challenging behaviors.</string>
    <string name="ga2">A. True</string>
    <string name="gb2">B. False</string>

    <string name="gq3">3. What is one way to help a person with dementia feel more comfortable in social situations?</string>
    <string name="ga3">A. Avoid socializing with them altogether</string>
    <string name="gb3">B. Provide clear and simple instructions for social events</string>
    <string name="gc3">C. Pressure them to participate in social events</string>
    <string name="gd3">D. Criticize them for their social behavior</string>

    <string name="gq4">4. What is one way to prevent falls and other accidents in a person with dementia?</string>
    <string name="ga4">A. Keep their living space cluttered and disorganized</string>
    <string name="gb4">B. Remove tripping hazards and install handrails and grab bars</string>
    <string name="gc4">C. Encourage them to move around quickly and without assistance</string>
    <string name="gd4">D. Leave sharp objects within their reach</string>

    <string name="gq5">5.  It is helpful to remind a person with dementia of past memories and events.</string>
    <string name="ga5">A. True</string>
    <string name="gb5">B. False</string>

    <string name="gq6">6. What is one way to help a person with dementia maintain their independence?</string>
    <string name="ga6">A. Do everything for them without asking for their input or assistance</string>
    <string name="gb6">B. Encourage them to participate in activities they enjoy</string>
    <string name="gc6">C. Limit their access to familiar objects and activities</string>
    <string name="gd6">D. Keep them isolated from the community</string>

    <string name="gq7">7. What is one way to help a person with dementia feel valued and respected?</string>
    <string name="ga7">A. Treat them like a child</string>
    <string name="gb7">B. Talk down to them or use baby talk</string>
    <string name="gc7">C. Provide opportunities for them to make choices and decisions</string>
    <string name="gd7">D. Ignore their feelings and concerns</string>

    <string name="gq8">8. It is important to allow a person with dementia to express their emotions, even if those emotions are negative.</string>
    <string name="ga8">A. True</string>
    <string name="gb8">B. False</string>

    <string name="gq9">9. What is one way to help a person with dementia stay connected with their loved ones?</string>
    <string name="ga9">A. Isolate them from their friends and family</string>
    <string name="gb9">B. Encourage them to avoid socializing with others</string>
    <string name="gc9">C. Provide opportunities for them to communicate with loved ones regularly</string>
    <string name="gd9">D. Discourage loved ones from visiting or communicating with them</string>

    <string name="gq10">10. What is one way to help a person with dementia feel more comfortable and at ease?</string>
    <string name="ga10">A. Speak loudly and quickly to them</string>
    <string name="gb10">B. Avoid touching or physical contact</string>
    <string name="gc10">C. Use humor and sarcasm when communicating with them</string>
    <string name="gd10">D. Speak to them in a calm and reassuring tone</string>


</resources>